To really see the details of how counties are grouped into clusters,
要真正地详细了解郡县是如何分组成聚类的
we have to look at the trained k-means model attributes.
我们需要查看训练过的 k 均值模型的属性
To get these attributes,
为了获得这些属性
we first have to find where our model is stored in S3,
首先需要知道模型存储在 S3 上的什么位置
retrieving it by name.
可以通过名称检索
Word saved is defined by our output path,
保存位置由输出路径确定
which is defined by our prefix,
输出路径由 prefix
our k-means job name,
K 均值作业名称
and this extension output/model.tar.gz.
以及扩展 output/model.tar.gz 组成
I just copied this from when I called fit above,
我从在上面调用 fit 的部分复制了该作业名称
but you can also find this in your AWS training jobs console.
不过也可以在 AWS 训练作业控制台中找到该名称
Then I'm downloading and unzipping the model file,
然后下载并解压缩模型文件
saving it as model algo-1.
保存为 model_algo-1
Then just as we did with the PCA model,
与 PCA 模型一样
I'm loading in those model details using our MXNet Library and loading it in as an array,
使用 mxnet 库加载这些模型数据并加载为数组
and I can print out those values.
输出这些值
This time, I can see that k-means actually just has one set of model parameters,
可以看出 这次 k 均值只有一组模型参数
and there are no names associated with it.
并且没有相关的名称
These values are actually our cluster centroids,
这些值其实是聚类形心
the location of each cluster identified by our k-means model.
表示 k 均值模型中每个聚类的位置
The location is a 70 point in PCA component space,
位置在 PCA 模型空间里是一个 7 维数据点
since that's the kind of data we passed into this model for training.
因为我们向此模型里传入的训练数据就是 7 维的
So in this next cell,
在下个单元格中
I'm getting those centuroids from the model attribute array.
从模型属性数组中获取这些形心
I can see I have eight clusters here and R seven components.
可以看到 这里有 8 个聚类以及 7 个成分
So this is the location of cluster zero in component space.
这是聚类 0 在成分空间里的位置
But this table alone is a bit difficult to translate into meaningful relationships.
但是单看这个表格 很难判断数据之间的关系
We can look at values and see which
我们可以看看哪些值最高
have the highest values and which have the lowest ones,
哪些值最低
but there's another way to visualize this.
不过还有另一种可视化方法
Seven dimensions can't be visualized in normal space,
我们不能在普通的空间里可视化 7 维数据
but I can look at this data as a heatmap.
但是可以通过热图的形式查看
On the x-axis, I have a cluster label zero through seven,
X 轴表示从 0 到 7 的聚类标签
and on the y, I have our components, C1 through C7.
Y 轴表示从 c1 到 c7 的成分
This heatmap is basically showing me which of
这个热图可以告诉我
these weights is most important in defining a cluster.
哪些权重在定义聚类方面最重要
One thing that sticks out is our cluster two.
聚类 2 比较突出
I can see that for this cluster,
可以看到这个聚类
it has a really high value for a component one.
对应了很高的 c1 值
Now if, you've forgotten what these components exactly correspond to,
如果你忘记这些成分到底对应什么
you can use the display component function from above.
可以使用上面的 display_component 函数
This takes in our DataFrame V,
它的参数包括 DataFrame V
a list of features,
特征列表
and a component number.
以及成分编号
I'm going to examine our first component again.
再看看第一个成分的组成
So now, this is telling us what demographic features make up component one,
这个图显示了组成成分 1 的人口统计学特征
and when I go back to this heatmap,
再回到这个热图上
it gives me a little more insight into what exactly defines our cluster two.
现在可以更清晰地知道聚类 2 是由哪些特征定义的
Component four also looks like an interesting one,
成分 4 看起来也比较有意思
it has a low value for cluster two,
它对应的聚类 2 的值很低
but high values for cluster zero and cluster seven.
但是对应的聚类 0 和聚类 7 的值很高
So let's take a look at that one.
我们看看这个成分
So by looking at our component makeup and this heatmap,
我们可以通过查看成分组成图和这个热图
we can really start to tell something about the makeup of each cluster.
判断出每个聚类的组成
But now, what does this have to do with our actual county data?
但是这与实际郡县数据有何关系？
You may be wondering which of our counties
你可能会疑问 哪些郡县聚类到一起
are clustered together and found to be most similar.
并且最为相似
So we can also map the cluster labels back to each data point,
我们可以将聚类标签映射到每个数据点（每个郡县）
each county, and see which of them were grouped in the same cluster.
看看哪些郡县分组到同一个聚类中
So here, I'm actually adding labels column to our transformed counties DataFrame.
我在这里向 counties_transformed DataFrame 添加了标签列
I can sort it and see which are clustered in cluster zero for example.
我可以排序 并查看在聚类 0 里有哪些郡县
We can see the variety of counties in cluster
查看前几个数据点就能看到
zero just from looking at the first few data points.
聚类 0 里的各种郡县
We can see datapoints in Georgia,
可以看到乔治亚州 路易斯安那州
Louisiana, Florida, and Virginia for example.
佛罗里达州和弗吉尼亚州的数据点
I can look at just one cluster at a time by getting
一次也可以仅查看一个聚类
a label equal to a certain cluster number that I'm interested in.
将标签设为我感兴趣的聚类编号即可
So if I want to look at counties that are all grouped into cluster one, I can.
我也可以查看聚类 1 里的所有郡县
These are still sorted by their original alphabetical order.
这些数据依然按照原来的字母顺序排序
I think it's interesting to know that these counties have
有意思的是 这些郡县具有相似性
similar characteristics as given by our principle components,
可以从主成分中判断出来
even though they're in different states for example.
虽然它们位于不同的州
So this analysis is the end of this notebook.
这就是这个 notebook 的最终分析结果
You've successfully completed population segmentation.
你已经成功地完成了人口细分任务
This type of information is most often used to create
此类信息经常用于
localized marketing campaigns that want to target
制定本地化的营销活动
a variety of regions based on demographics similarities.
旨在根据人口相似性定位到不同的区域
Now, I'd encourage you to play around with the visualizations in this notebook.
建议你尝试下这个 notebook 的可视化图表
As one last step,
最后一步
if you decide you're entirely done,
如果你已经完全操作完毕
I suggest you take further resource cleaning steps,
建议继续完成资源清理步骤
and I've linked to some relevant documentation here.
我在这里提供了相关文档的链接
To do a thorough cleanup,
为了完成彻底的清理步骤
you'll actually want to go to your main Amazon SageMaker console.
你需要转到主 Amazon SageMaker 控制台
You'll want to click on "Endpoint",
点击“Endpoint”
"End point configurations," and "Models" and manually delete them from the console.
“End point configurations”以及“Models”然后从控制台里手动删除资源
You can also go to S3 and delete anything in the S3 bucket,
还可以转到 S3 并删除 S3 存储桶里的所有资源
this is a good habit to get into.
建议养成良好习惯
Now, using all that you've learned in this lesson,
现在 运用你在这节课所学的知识
you should feel prepared to tackle any unsupervised task.
你可以解决任何非监督式任务了
Next, we'll recap what you've learned,
接下来我们将总结所学的知识
and then move on to supervised learning.
然后继续学习监督式学习